[{"question": "Express: summation ((a_i)**2 * (b_i)**2) <br>using linear algebra", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "a @ np.diag(a) @ b @ np.diag(b)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "a @ np.diag(a) + np.diag(b) @ b", "correct": false}, {"answer": "a @ np.diag(a) @ np.diag(b) @ b", "correct": true}, {"answer": "a @ b @ np.diag(a) @ np.diag(b)", "correct": false}], "tag": "summation iteration dot_product", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "What will be the shape of the final matrix, if the 4 matrices below are multiplied in the way shown:<br>np.array([1, 1]) @ np.array([[1, 2], [3, 4], [5, 6]).T @ np.array([1, 2, 3]).T", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "Error", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(1)", "correct": true}, {"answer": "(1, 3)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(2, 3)", "correct": false}], "tag": "matrices", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "What will be the shape of the final matrix, if the 4 matrices below are multiplied in the way shown:<br>np.array([1, 1]) @ np.array([[1, 2], [3, 4], [5, 6]).T @ np.array([1, 2, 3])", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "Error", "correct": true}, {"answer": "(1)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(1, 3)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(2, 3)", "correct": false}], "tag": "matrices", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "The determinant of a matrix is a", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "scalar", "correct": true}, {"answer": "vector", "correct": false}, {"answer": "matrix", "correct": false}, {"answer": "None of the above", "correct": false}], "tag": "determinant", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "Find the determinant of the following matrix:<br>np.array([[1, 2, 3], [2, 2, 2]])", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "0", "correct": false}, {"answer": "3", "correct": false}, {"answer": "1", "correct": false}, {"answer": "determinant can be calculated only for square matrices", "correct": true}], "tag": "determinant", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true about the below matrix:<br>np.array([[1, 2, 3], [2, 2, 2], [1, 1, 1]])", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "It is a non-singular matrix", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Rank of the matrix is 3", "correct": false}, {"answer": "It is a singular matrix", "correct": true}, {"answer": "The inverse of the matrix is real and finite", "correct": false}], "tag": "matrices", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "The advantage of using linear algebra over solve_bvp to solve boundary value problems is that", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "It can solve a non-linear system of equations", "correct": false}, {"answer": "No need of an initial guess", "correct": true}, {"answer": "Requires very few points", "correct": false}, {"answer": "All of the above", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy applications", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "Which of the folllowing matrices are in reduced row echelon form:<br>1: np.array([[1, 2, 3], [0, 1, 0], [0, 0, 1]])<br>2: np.array([[1, 0, 1], [0, 1, 1], [0, 0, 0]])<br>3: np.array([[0, 1, 0], [0, 0, 1], [0, 0, 0]])", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "1, 2, 3", "correct": false}, {"answer": "1, 2", "correct": false}, {"answer": "2, 3", "correct": false}, {"answer": "3", "correct": true}], "tag": "reduced_row_echelon matrices", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "Which of the following  is not true about a dot product", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "It is the sum of the element-wise product of 2 arrays", "correct": false}, {"answer": "square root of a vector's dot product with itself is the magnitude of the vector", "correct": false}, {"answer": "It can also produce a vector", "correct": true}, {"answer": "It can be used to find the angle between 2 vectors", "correct": false}], "tag": "dot_product", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}, {"question": "Which of the following is a property of dot products for the vectors A, B, C.", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "If A.B = A.C; then B=C", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(A.B).C = C.(A.B)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "A and B are orthogonal if A.B = 1", "correct": false}, {"answer": "A.(B+C) = A.B + A.C", "correct": true}], "tag": "dot_product", "lecture_file": "16_linear_algebra"}]